<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on fmiki works</title><link>https://fmikiw.github.io/cv/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on fmiki works</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://fmikiw.github.io/cv/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://fmikiw.github.io/cv/docs/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fmikiw.github.io/cv/docs/publications/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="publications"&gt;Publications&lt;a class="anchor" href="#publications"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="first-author-publications"&gt;First-Author Publications&lt;a class="anchor" href="#first-author-publications"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol reversed&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;M. Fujita, N. Sugiura, S. Kouketsu

 (2024).
 &lt;i&gt;Prediction of Atmospheric Profiles With Machine Learning Using the Signature Method&lt;/i&gt;. Geophysical Research Letters.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1029/2023gl106403" target="_blank"&gt;10.1029/2023gl106403&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;M. Fujita, T. Fukuda, I. Ueki, Q. Moteki, T. Ushiyama, K. Yoneyama

 (2020).
 &lt;i&gt;Experimental Observations of Precipitable Water Vapor over the Open Ocean Collected by Autonomous Surface Vehicles for Real-Time Monitoring Applications&lt;/i&gt;. SOLA.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2151/sola.16a-004" target="_blank"&gt;10.2151/sola.16a-004&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;M. FUJITA, T. SATO, T. YAMADA, S. KAWAZOE, M. NAKANO, K. ITO

 (2019).
 &lt;i&gt;Analyses of Extreme Precipitation Associated with the Kinugawa River Flood in September 2015 Using a Large Ensemble Downscaling Experiment&lt;/i&gt;. Journal of the Meteorological Society of Japan. Ser. II.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2151/jmsj.2019-022" target="_blank"&gt;10.2151/jmsj.2019-022&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;M. Fujita, R. Mizuta, M. Ishii, H. Endo, T. Sato, Y. Okada, S. Kawazoe, S. Sugimoto, K. Ishihara, S. Watanabe

 (2019).
 &lt;i&gt;Precipitation Changes in a Climate With 2-K Surface Warming From Large Ensemble Simulations Using 60-km Global and 20-km Regional Atmospheric Models&lt;/i&gt;. Geophysical Research Letters.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1029/2018gl079885" target="_blank"&gt;10.1029/2018gl079885&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;M. Fujita, T. Sato

 (2017).
 &lt;i&gt;Observed behaviours of precipitable water vapour and precipitation intensity in response to upper air profiles estimated from surface air temperature&lt;/i&gt;. SCIENTIFIC REPORTS.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-017-04443-9" target="_blank"&gt;10.1038/s41598-017-04443-9&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;M. Fujita, A. Wada, T. Iwabuchi, C. Rocken

 (2014).
 &lt;i&gt;Tropospheric monitoring over the ocean using shipborne GNSS receiver&lt;/i&gt;. Proceedings of the 27th International Technical Meeting of the Satellite Division of The Institute of Navigation (ION GNSS&amp;#43; 2014).
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;M. Fujita, H. Takahashi, M. Hara

 (2013).
 &lt;i&gt;Diurnal cycle of precipitation over the eastern Indian Ocean off Sumatra Island during different phases of Indian Ocean Dipole&lt;/i&gt;. ATMOSPHERIC SCIENCE LETTERS.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/asl2.432" target="_blank"&gt;10.1002/asl2.432&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;M. Fujita, A. Wada, T. Iwabuchi, C. Rocken

 (2012).
 &lt;i&gt;GPS Precpitable Water Vapor Dataset for Climate Science&lt;/i&gt;. PROCEEDINGS OF THE 25TH INTERNATIONAL TECHNICAL MEETING OF THE SATELLITE DIVISION OF THE INSTITUTE OF NAVIGATION (ION GNSS 2012).
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;M. Fujita, K. Yoneyama, S. Mori, T. Nasuno, M. Satoh

 (2011).
 &lt;i&gt;Diurnal Convection Peaks over the Eastern Indian Ocean off Sumatra during Different MJO Phases&lt;/i&gt;. JOURNAL OF THE METEOROLOGICAL SOCIETY OF JAPAN.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2151/jmsj.2011-A22" target="_blank"&gt;10.2151/jmsj.2011-A22&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;M. Fujita, F. Kimura, M. Yoshizaki

 (2010).
 &lt;i&gt;Morning Precipitation Peak over the Strait of Malacca under a Calm Condition&lt;/i&gt;. MONTHLY WEATHER REVIEW.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1175/2009MWR3068.1" target="_blank"&gt;10.1175/2009MWR3068.1&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;M. Fujita, F. Kimura, K. Yoneyama, M. Yoshizaki

 (2008).
 &lt;i&gt;Verification of precipitable water vapor estimated from shipborne GPS measurements&lt;/i&gt;. GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH LETTERS.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1029/2008GL033764" target="_blank"&gt;10.1029/2008GL033764&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;M. Fujita, T. Sasaki, F. Kimura

 (2006).
 &lt;i&gt;A Dramatic Daytime Decrease in Water Vapor over Coastal Thailand&lt;/i&gt;. SOLA.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2151/sola.2006-013" target="_blank"&gt;10.2151/sola.2006-013&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id="co-authored-publications"&gt;Co-authored Publications&lt;a class="anchor" href="#co-authored-publications"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol reversed&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;Y. Yamada, T. Nasuno, M. Nakano, C. Kodama, M. Hishinuma, T. Miyakawa, M. Fujita

 (2025).
 &lt;i&gt;Evaluation of the Relationship between Seasonal Tropical Cyclone Activity and Rainfall in Japan Using a Large-Ensemble Simulation&lt;/i&gt;. .
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2151/sola.21b-002" target="_blank"&gt;10.2151/sola.21b-002&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;S. Kawazoe, M. Inatsu, M. Fujita, S. Sugimoto, Y. Okada, S. Watanabe

 (2023).
 &lt;i&gt;Evaluation of tornadic environments and their trends and projected changes in Japan&lt;/i&gt;. npj Climate and Atmospheric Science.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41612-023-00524-x" target="_blank"&gt;10.1038/s41612-023-00524-x&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;K. Yoneyama, S. Yokoi, M. Fujita, A. Seiki, M. Katsumata, B. Geng, T. Fukuda

 (2023).
 &lt;i&gt;Atmospheric Convection Research Using Autonomous Surface Vehicles&lt;/i&gt;. MAUSAM.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.54302/mausam.v74i2.5904" target="_blank"&gt;10.54302/mausam.v74i2.5904&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;H. Kawase, T. Yamazaki, S. Sugimoto, T. Sasai, R. Ito, T. Hamada, M. Kuribayashi, M. Fujita, A. Murata, M. Nosaka, H. Sasaki

 (2020).
 &lt;i&gt;Changes in extremely heavy and light snow-cover winters due to global warming over high mountainous areas in central Japan&lt;/i&gt;. PROGRESS IN EARTH AND PLANETARY SCIENCE.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/s40645-020-0322-x" target="_blank"&gt;10.1186/s40645-020-0322-x&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;Y. Nakagawa, Y. Onoue, S. Kawahara, F. Araki, K. Koyamada, D. Matsuoka, Y. Ishikawa, M. Fujita, S. Sugimoto, Y. Okada, S. Kawazoe, S. Watanabe, M. Ishii, R. Mizuta, A. Murata, H. Kawase

 (2020).
 &lt;i&gt;Development of a system for efficient content-based retrieval to analyze large volumes of climate data&lt;/i&gt;. PROGRESS IN EARTH AND PLANETARY SCIENCE.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/s40645-019-0315-9" target="_blank"&gt;10.1186/s40645-019-0315-9&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;S. KAWAZOE, M. FUJITA, S. SUGIMOTO, Y. OKADA, S. WATANABE

 (2020).
 &lt;i&gt;Projected Changes of Extremely Cool Summer Days over Northeastern Japan Simulated by 20 km-mesh Large Ensemble Experiment&lt;/i&gt;. Journal of the Meteorological Society of Japan. Ser. II.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2151/jmsj.2020-067" target="_blank"&gt;10.2151/jmsj.2020-067&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;W. Shingo, F. Mikiko, K. Sho, S. Shiori, O. Yasuko, M. Ryo, I. Masayoshi

 (2019).
 &lt;i&gt;Frequency Change of Clear-Air Turbulence over the North Pacific under 2 K Global Warming - Ensemble Projections Using a 60-km Atmospheric General Circulation Model&lt;/i&gt;. JOURNAL OF THE METEOROLOGICAL SOCIETY OF JAPAN.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2151/jmsj.2019-038" target="_blank"&gt;10.2151/jmsj.2019-038&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;N. Mori, T. Shimura, K. Yoshida, R. Mizuta, Y. Okada, M. Fujita, T. Khujanazarov, E. Nakakita

 (2019).
 &lt;i&gt;Future changes in extreme storm surges based on mega-ensemble projection using 60-km resolution atmospheric global circulation model&lt;/i&gt;. Coastal Engineering Journal.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/21664250.2019.1586290" target="_blank"&gt;10.1080/21664250.2019.1586290&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;S. T., K. H., K. Y., Y. J., S. S., Y. T., S. H., F. M., I. T.

 (2019).
 &lt;i&gt;Future Projection of Extreme Heavy Snowfall Events With a 5-km Large Ensemble Regional Climate Simulation&lt;/i&gt;. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JD030781" target="_blank"&gt;10.1029/2019JD030781&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;K. Ariyoshi, S. Nishida, Y. Machida, T. Iinuma, H. Uchida, A. Nagano, T. Hasegawa, T. Miyama, Y. Miyazawa, M. Wakita, T. Kuwatani, K. Aoike, M. Fujita, A. Kuwano-Yoshida, A. To, K. Ichikawa

 (2018).
 &lt;i&gt;A Total Station Plan Combined with “D/V Chikyu” and DONET:Simultaneous Observation from Seafloor to Atmosphere&lt;/i&gt;. 2018 OCEANS - MTS/IEEE Kobe Techno-Oceans (OTO).
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/OCEANSKOBE.2018.8559382" target="_blank"&gt;10.1109/OCEANSKOBE.2018.8559382&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;M. RASMY, T. KOIKE, P. LAWFORD, M. HARA, M. FUJITA, F. KIMURA

 (2015).
 &lt;i&gt;ASSESSMENT OF FUTURE WATER RESOURCES IN THE TONE RIVER BASIN USING A COMBINED DYNAMICAL-STATISTICAL DOWNSCALING APPROACH&lt;/i&gt;. B1.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2208/jscejhe.71.I_73" target="_blank"&gt;10.2208/jscejhe.71.I_73&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;Y. Wakazuki, M. Hara, M. Fujita, C. Suzuki, X. Ma, F. Kimura

 (2015).
 &lt;i&gt;Effect of climate change on the snow disappearance date in mountainous areas of central Japan&lt;/i&gt;. HYDROLOGICAL RESEARCH LETTERS.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3178/hrl.9.20" target="_blank"&gt;10.3178/hrl.9.20&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;M. RASMY, M. SHRESTHA, T. KOIKE, M. HARA, M. FUJITA, F. KIMURA

 (2014).
 &lt;i&gt;A COMBINED DYNAMICAL/STATISTICAL DOWNSCALING APPROACH FOR ASSESSING FUTURE OF WATER RESOURCES IN THE TONE RIVER BASIN, JAPAN&lt;/i&gt;. B1.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2208/jscejhe.70.I_187" target="_blank"&gt;10.2208/jscejhe.70.I_187&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;X. Ma, H. Kawase, S. Adachi, M. Fujita, H. Takahashi, M. Hara, N. Ishizaki, T. Yoshikane, H. Hatsushika, Y. Wakazuki, F. Kimura

 (2013).
 &lt;i&gt;Simulating river discharge in a snowy region of Japan using output from a regional climate model&lt;/i&gt;. Advances in Geosciences.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5194/adgeo-35-55-2013" target="_blank"&gt;10.5194/adgeo-35-55-2013&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;M. RASMY, C. TANDA, P. Ann, JARANILLA-SANCHEZ, T. KOIKE, M. HARA, M. FUJITA, H. KAWASE

 (2013).
 &lt;i&gt;IDENTIFYING GAPS AND OPPORTUNITIES BETWEEN STATISTICAL AND DYNAMICAL DOWNSCALING APPROACHES OVER SHIKOKU ISLAND, JAPAN&lt;/i&gt;. J. JSCE, Ser. B1.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2208/jscejhe.69.I_133" target="_blank"&gt;10.2208/jscejhe.69.I_133&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;H. Kawase, T. Yoshikane, M. Hara, M. Fujita, N. Ishizaki, F. Kimura, H. Hatsushika

 (2012).
 &lt;i&gt;Downscaling of Snow Cover Changes in the Late 20th Century Using a Past Climate Simulation Method over Central Japan&lt;/i&gt;. SOLA.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2151/sola.2012-016" target="_blank"&gt;10.2151/sola.2012-016&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;K. Yasunaga, K. Yoneyama, Q. Moteki, M. Fujita, Y. N, Takayabu, J. Suzuki, T. Ushiyama, B. Mapes

 (2010).
 &lt;i&gt;Characteristics of 3–4- and 6–8-Day Period Disturbances Observed over the Tropical Indian Ocean&lt;/i&gt;. Mon. Wea. Rev..
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1175/2010MWR3469.1" target="_blank"&gt;10.1175/2010MWR3469.1&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;K. Yoneyama, Y. Masumoto, Y. Kuroda, M. Katsumata, K. Mizuno, Y. Takayabu, M. Yoshizaki, A. Shareef, Y. Fujiyoshi, M. McPhaden, V. Murty, R. Shirooka, K. Yasunaga, H. Yamada, N. Sato, T. Ushiyama, Q. Moteki, A. Seiki, M. Fujita, K. Ando, H. Hase, I. Ueki, T. Horii, C. Yokoyama, T. Miyakawa

 (2008).
 &lt;i&gt;MISMO FIELD EXPERIMENT IN THE EQUATORIAL INDIAN OCEAN&lt;/i&gt;. BULLETIN OF THE AMERICAN METEOROLOGICAL SOCIETY.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1175/2008BAMS2519.1" target="_blank"&gt;10.1175/2008BAMS2519.1&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;Q. Moteki, R. Shirooka, H. Kubota, T. Ushiyama, K. Reddy, K. Yoneyama, M. Katsumata, N. Sato, K. Yasunaga, H. Yamada, B. Geng, M. Fujita, M. Yoshizaki, H. Uyeda, T. Chuda

 (2008).
 &lt;i&gt;Mechanism of the northward propagation of mesoscale convective systems observed on 15 June 2005 during PALAU2005&lt;/i&gt;. JOURNAL OF GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH-ATMOSPHERES.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1029/2008JD009793" target="_blank"&gt;10.1029/2008JD009793&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;K. Yoneyama, M. Fujita, N. Sato, M. Fujiwara, Y. Inai, F. Hasebe

 (2008).
 &lt;i&gt;Correction for Radiation Dry Bias Found in RS92 Radiosonde Data during the MISMO Field Experiment&lt;/i&gt;. SOLA.
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2151/sola.2008-004" target="_blank"&gt;10.2151/sola.2008-004&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id="articles-published-in-japanese"&gt;Articles Published in Japanese&lt;a class="anchor" href="#articles-published-in-japanese"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;山崎剛, 佐々井崇博, 川瀬宏明, 杉本志織, 大楽浩司, 伊東瑠衣, 佐々木秀孝, 藤田実季子

 (2019).
 &lt;i&gt;5km力学的ダウンスケーリングデータセット（SI-CAT DDS5TK）の概要&lt;/i&gt;. シミュレーション.
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
 &lt;li&gt;若月泰孝, 原政之, 藤田実季子, 馬燮銚, 井上忠雄, 木村富士男, 小池俊雄

 (2016).
 &lt;i&gt;気候差分ダウンスケーリング法による関東・中部山岳域の確率論的気候変化予測&lt;/i&gt;. 土木学会論文集 B1(水工学).
 
 DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2208/jscejhe.72.i_55" target="_blank"&gt;10.2208/jscejhe.72.i_55&lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;/li&gt;
 
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://fmikiw.github.io/cv/docs/cv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fmikiw.github.io/cv/docs/cv/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="about"&gt;About&lt;a class="anchor" href="#about"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="profile-information"&gt;Profile Information&lt;a class="anchor" href="#profile-information"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name: Mikiko FUJITA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Affiliation: &lt;a href="https://www.jamstec.go.jp/"&gt;Japan Agency for Marine-Earth Science and Technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Degree: Ph.D. (University of Tsukuba)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ORCID iD: &lt;a href="https://orcid.org/0000-0001-6125-060X"&gt;https://orcid.org/0000-0001-6125-060X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="research-interests"&gt;Research Interests&lt;a class="anchor" href="#research-interests"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Climate-driven changes in air-sea interaction and their impacts on moisture and precipitation extremes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPS/GNSS Meteorology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="links"&gt;Links&lt;a class="anchor" href="#links"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://researchmap.jp/Mikiko_Fujita?lang=en"&gt;researchmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://scholar.google.co.jp/citations?user=E7vBsNUAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;Google Scholar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Mikiko-Fujita"&gt;ResearchGate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>